No place to run. No reason to hide.
Open Range is a western, drama, action film directed by Kevin Costner.
A former gunslinger is forced to take up arms again when he and
his cattle crew are threatened by a corrupt lawman.
Charley Waite, played by Kevin Costner.
Boss Spearman, played by Robert Duvall.
Denton Baxter, played by Michael Gambon.
Percy, played by Michael Jeter.
Button, played by Diego Luna.
Sheriff Poole, played by James Russo.
Open Range is a 2003 American revisionist Western film directed and co-produced by Kevin Costner,
written by Craig Storper and based on the novel The Open Range Men by Lauran Paine.
It stars Robert Duvall and Costner, with Annette Bening, Michael
Gambon, and Michael Jeter appearing in supporting roles.
It presents a range war that happens when free-grazing herder "Boss" Spearman (Duvall) and his
cowboys enter the Montana territory of cattle baron Denton Baxter (Gambon).
The film was the final on-screen appearance of Jeter, who died before it was released, and
was dedicated to his memory, as well as to Costner's parents, Bill and Sharon.
It was a box-office success and was critically praised.
The film explores themes of gunslinger, montana, horse, beef, ranger.
The tone is emotional.